<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>#</title>
 <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://no3371.github.io/blog/"/>
 <updated>2021-09-29T08:30:58+00:00</updated>
 <id>https://no3371.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
   
 
   
   <entry>
     <title>Unity: iOS PVRTC Compression Requires Square Textures</title>
     <link href="https://no3371.github.io/blog/posts/unity-ios-pvrtc-compression-requires-square-textures/en"/>
     <updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
     <id>https://no3371.github.io/posts/unity-ios-pvrtc-compression-requires-square-textures/unity-ios-pvrtc-compression-requires-square-textures</id>
     <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today my collegue noticed that same animation looks different on iOS and Android, after digging around for a short period, we figured that the related atlas has different imported size on Android &amp;amp; iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that by default, Unity select PVRTC compression format for iOS to support older devices (~2013). PVRTC format requires square textures, &lt;strong&gt;if the texture is not square, Unity stretch it without warning you.&lt;/strong&gt; For not-so-old (2014~) iOS devices, ATSC is recommened and it supports non-square textures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.unity3d.com/Manual/class-TextureImporterOverride.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;iOS and tvOS
For Apple devices that use the A8 chip (2014) or above, ATSC is the recommended texture compression format for RGB and RGBA textures. This format allows you to choose between texture quality and size on a granular level: all the way from eight bits/pixel (4x4 block size) down to 0.89 bits/pixel (12x12 block size). If support for older devices is needed, or you want additional Crunch compression, then Apple devices support ETC/ETC2 formats starting with A7 chip (2013). For even older devices, PVRTC is the compression format to use. On iOS, Unity’s default texture compression format is PVRTC, for the broadest possible compatibility. ASTC is preferred, but is not supported on A7 devices (the very first Metal-enabled devices) and will be unpacked at runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
   </entry>
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
   <entry>
     <title>Unity Memory Leak With GooglePlay Plugins</title>
     <link href="https://no3371.github.io/blog/posts/unity-memory-leak-with-google-play-plugins/en"/>
     <updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
     <id>https://no3371.github.io/posts/unity-memory-leak-with-google-play-plugins/unity-memory-leak-with-google-play-plugins</id>
     <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So it seems if you have Google Play Plugins in your Unity project and you have &lt;strong&gt;Auto Resolution On Build&lt;/strong&gt; toggled on in Play Service Resolver (Android), everytime you build, some junk is left in the heap and counted in ManagedHeap.UsedSize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unity will try to GC.Collect from time to time and that makes Editor freeze without any of the leak gets collected, FeelsBadMan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unity 2018.4.35f1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GooglePlayPlugins 1.5.0&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
   </entry>
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
 

</feed>