<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>#</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://blog.3371.online/"/>
 <updated>2022-01-25T19:04:47+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://blog.3371.online</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
   <entry>
     <title>Free &amp; Private PushBullet with PatchBay</title>
     <link href="http://blog.3371.online/posts/free-private-pushbullet-with-patchbay/en"/>
     <updated>2021-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
     <id>http://blog.3371.online/posts/free-private-pushbullet-with-patchbay/free-private-pushbullet-with-patchbay</id>
     <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://patchbay.pub&quot;&gt;PatchBay&lt;/a&gt; is a free and public service that “patch” Http &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt; together. For example, you &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://patchbay.pub/123&lt;/code&gt; and POST “321” to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://patchbay.pub/123&lt;/code&gt;, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; side will receive “321”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds boring, eh? But it could be the most clever thing I’ve seen these years, and it’s free for anyone to use without any authentication, which enable a lot of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made several personal tools based on PatchBay, for example, PushBullet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;400: Invalid request&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/1f16e99fc1b49cdd4be25adc9aaab025.js&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The powershell script takes 1 parameter: the channel name. Channel Name is the only input to PatchBay that decide where you &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; from/&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt; to, so as long as no one share the same channel name with you, we can say the channel is yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed, the script actually use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://patchbay.pub/pubsub/&lt;/code&gt;, which is the pubsub mode of PatchBay, this means all PC running this script will receive data POSTed to the pubsub channel, not just 1 PC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mainly POST stuff I wanna read later with curl from my joc PC to my home PC, if I really need it, I can also POST from my Android phone, working with PatchBay feels really nice and easy, because you can do Http &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt; everywhere as long as you are connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why I don’t use the actual PushBullet but this is that, I don’t want to login on my job PC, I’m the type that feels insecure and cares alot about my privacy. For people like me, things like PatchBat is really awesome, though it’s not actually “secure”, but its login-less nature is trully useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT 2021/09/22
It seems patchbay.pub is down :sad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT 2021/10/02
So I grabbed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/schollz/duct&quot;&gt;duct&lt;/a&gt; and starting to host my own service for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose &lt;a href=&quot;vultr.com&quot;&gt;Vultr&lt;/a&gt; and deployed a machine and is now hosting the program on it. It was a fun and fresh experience, I learned about how domain name &amp;amp; dns works, how to setup linux systemd service, how to work with SElinux, etc. &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/hosting-a-web-service-on-vultr/en&quot;&gt;Here is a blog post about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
   </entry>
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
 
   
 

</feed>